<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-25T17:25:05+01:00</updated><id>hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bringing Ideas to Life Through Code</title><subtitle>Welcome to my personal portfolio! Here, you can explore more about my work, projects, and the skills I’ve developed as a web developer. Whether you&apos;re looking for collaboration, inspiration, or just curious about what I do, I&apos;m glad you visited my site!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Fibonacci-clock project</title><link href="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/my-fibonacci-clock-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fibonacci-clock project" /><published>2025-01-22T16:05:35+01:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T16:05:35+01:00</updated><id>hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/my-fibonacci-clock-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/my-fibonacci-clock-project.html"><![CDATA[<p>Below, you’ll find the Fibonacci Clock project I created. This clock presents time using the Fibonacci sequence, offering a unique and visually captivating way to keep track of the hours, minutes, and seconds.</p>

<p>Each circle on the clock represents a number in the Fibonacci sequence, with colors distinguishing between the hours, minutes, and seconds. It’s a playful yet functional design that I had a lot of fun building!</p>

<p>When you click on the clock, you’ll get more details about how it works, and you can even customize the colors to your liking.
Feel free to check it out and let me know what you think!</p>

<div id="iframe-clock" style="width: 100%; height: 500px; border: 1px solid #ccc;">
  <iframe src="https://mac-hills.github.io/fibonacci-clock/" style="width: 100%; height: 100%; border: none;" title="Embedded fibonacci clock">
  </iframe>
</div>

<p><a href="https://mac-hills.github.io/fibonacci-clock/" target="_blank">Click here to open the Fibonacci-clock full screen in a new window</a></p>

<h1 id="technical-details">Technical Details</h1>
<p>This project was built using Angular, a powerful framework for building dynamic web applications. I utilized Angular to create a responsive and interactive Fibonacci clock that’s both functional and visually appealing.</p>

<p>Once completed, I deployed the project to GitHub Pages, a free hosting service that allows me to share the clock with others easily. GitHub Pages serves the project directly from my GitHub repository, making it a simple and efficient way to host static websites.</p>

<p>Feel free to explore the source code on my GitHub repository to see how it all comes together!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Below, you’ll find the Fibonacci Clock project I created. This clock presents time using the Fibonacci sequence, offering a unique and visually captivating way to keep track of the hours, minutes, and seconds.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my portfolio!</title><link href="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/welcome-to-my-portfolio.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my portfolio!" /><published>2025-01-22T13:12:35+01:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T13:12:35+01:00</updated><id>hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/welcome-to-my-portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="hhtps://mac-hills.github.io/portfolio/jekyll/update/2025/01/22/welcome-to-my-portfolio.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome to my personal portfolio! I’m thrilled that you’ve decided to stop by and explore the work I’ve been passionate about. This portfolio is not just a showcase of my projects and skills but also a reflection of my journey into the world of IT and software development.</p>

<p>As someone transitioning from a career in education administration to the dynamic field of software development, I’ve discovered the joy of creating solutions that make life easier and more efficient. Every project I work on is an opportunity to learn something new, solve a problem, and challenge myself to grow.</p>

<p><strong>Here, you’ll find:</strong></p>

<p><strong><em>My Projects:</em></strong> A collection of the software and web development projects I’ve completed so far, showcasing my technical skills and creativity.</p>

<p><strong><em>Skills and Tools:</em></strong> The programming languages, frameworks, and tools I’ve mastered—and the ones I’m currently learning.</p>

<p><strong><em>Blog Posts:</em></strong> Insights and reflections on my journey as a developer, the challenges I’ve faced, and the lessons I’ve learned along the way.</p>

<p>This site is more than just a portfolio—it’s a space for collaboration and connection. If you’re a fellow developer, a potential employer, or just someone curious about my work, I’d love to hear from you. Don’t hesitate to reach out or leave a comment on any project that catches your eye.</p>

<p>Thank you for visiting my portfolio. Let’s build something great together!</p>

<p>Warm regards,Wannes Machiels</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to my personal portfolio! I’m thrilled that you’ve decided to stop by and explore the work I’ve been passionate about. This portfolio is not just a showcase of my projects and skills but also a reflection of my journey into the world of IT and software development.]]></summary></entry></feed>